<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?> 
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>Ethan Estrada: Posts tagged 'blog'</title>
  <description>Ethan Estrada: Posts tagged 'blog'</description>
  <link>http://eestrada.github.io/tags/blog.html</link>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 15:52:18 UT</lastBuildDate>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 15:52:18 UT</pubDate>
  <ttl>1800</ttl>
  <item>
   <title>Moving blogs</title>
   <link>http://eestrada.github.io/blog/2016/07/29/moving-blogs.html?utm_source=blog&amp;utm_medium=RSS</link>
   <guid>urn:http-eestrada-github-io:-blog-2016-07-29-moving-blogs-html</guid>
   <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2016 15:52:18 UT</pubDate>
   <description>&lt;html&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am moving blogging platforms and thought I should maybe explain why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past I have been hosting my blog on Google&amp;rsquo;s Blogger platform. This has served me pretty well over the years along with the limited number of posts I have made. However, as I have tried to expand the blog into more of a general website, it has been an uphill battle fighting against the workflow of the blogging system itself. I don&amp;rsquo;t forsee wordpress being much different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, one of my reasons for moving to my current setup was simplicity and control. I am using a static site generator now (ala Jekyll). The reasons for this being that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;I now directly control my own content&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t need to set up a wordpress server or anything of the sort&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;There should never be downtime since the site is statically hosted  on Github or S3 or whereever&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Inline with number 1, I can version control my content (with  something simple like git)&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;I can write my posts in MarkDown&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;I can embed source code styling instead of reaching out to  JavaScript libraries to do it dynamically at run time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like all these reasons. It also means I can theme the site however I like using simple HTML templates. I can also add whatever types of pages I want since in the end it is just static HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really, there are lots of reasons to use a static site generator. I am currently using &lt;a href="https://github.com/greghendershott/frog"&gt;frog&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;strong&gt;fr&lt;/strong&gt;ozen bl&lt;strong&gt;og&lt;/strong&gt; generator, written in a somewhat lesser known language called Racket (a dialect of Lisp descended from Scheme). I like the Lisp in general and Racket in specific. I want to support its increased usage and the best way to do that is to use projects that use it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to port over my old blog posts once I get a chance, although that may prove to be a bit of a chore. I&amp;rsquo;ll probably end up avoiding it for a super long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/html&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>